Contact

Phone

07900690022

Email

Charlotte@wearetwixt.com

Address

44 Plevna Road Hampton London TW12 2BP

Expertise

- Commercial awareness
- Inclusive Leader
- Accomplished writer
- · Confident public speaker.
- Problem-solver
- Web2>Web3 Consultant
- Excellent communication skills
- Change Management
- Integrated strategy
- · Brand and content strategy
- Customer Journey Mapping

Charlotte Bunyan

Strategic leader with exceptional management skills and 20 years industry experience. Specialising in **driving business growth through innovation**; informed by robust strategic insights. Keen eye for **market opportunities**, a wealth of experience in **creative technology** and a talent for managing complex initiatives to deliver **results that create commercial and cultural impact.**

Delivered **award-winning work** for a diverse range of organisations and brands, including Coty, Shiseido Group, Frasers Group, Unilever, Sony, Honda, HSBC, P&G, the Home Office, NHS, Pepsi as well as **mentoring and advising start-ups and scale-ups**.

Experience

CULT | Global Independent Creative Agency

Jan 2023 - : Managing Director

Defining Cross department OKR and initiating Leadership training to drive commercial success and continue growth trajectory in line with B-Corp accreditation. Developing agency reorganisation plans to deliver on vision and drive operational efficiencies to achieve **Staff/Cost ratios of 60%**

Concepting, and building the proposition and business case for the inaugural Metaverse Beauty Week (MBW): successfully securing 14 participating brands, delivering 30+ talks, masterclasses and workshops, 1.9B press reach, 240+ pieces of press coverage, 30,000 attendees across 50 countries, on Decentraland, Spatial, Roblox. Culminating in the world's largest showcase of beauty AR experiences at Flagship Oxford Street store, FlannelsX Driving a new biz opportunity pipeline of £1.3m Personally delivered Metaverse 101 training sessions for THG, Neutrogena, Shiseido Group and Futures Generation with 100% approval rating.

May 2021 - Feb 2023: Chief Strategy Officer

Oct 2019 - May 2021: Head of Strategy & Futures

Delivering executional excellence across all strategy and futures work; identifying

opportunities for innovation and unlocking new opportunities with high growth client groups. 100% pitch win rate and client growth planning integral to securing 900% EBITDA growth in 2021, and sustained 30% margin into 2022.

Leading Key projects including:

- Shiseido: Defining and launching a proactive innovation concept for Shiseido's 150 year celebration; an Al powered NFT community co-created with five female beauty and tech pioneers. Achieving +20m, addressable reach through PR, Limited edition 150 NFT drop oversubscribed by +1500% with 100% positive sentiment. Unlocking global and European opportunities across Shiseido Group worth over £750K.
- Coty: Sally Hansen: 6 yrs driving ever-improving ROI and YoY cost efficiencies, supporting continuous brand growth to 50%+ marketshare; formulating SH's TikTok strategy to achieve 150M+ MAU; 413% uplift in average % of FYP views, 835x higher engagement rate vs platform avg.
- Jack Wills Xmas: influencer-led campaign to reposition Jack Wills and drive relevance
 to Gen Z audience, driving 12% YoY Sales growth with an 11% increase in avg basket
 spend and +711% ER compared to industry average; Enabling a subsequent full year's
 retainer across 4 other campaigns, driving growth and revenue of £1.2m for 2022
- Cult Futures: Launching DressX digital garments collection, two NFT drops, accompanied by insights reports and shareable learning; achieving R+D savings of £70k, Providing consultancy to Yoox Net-A-Porter on Web3 pilots and securing Web3 opportunities with 3 other luxe brands.

Accomplishments

Co-Founder:

 Twixt: Europe's only dedicated resource and survival guide for parenting tweens

Board Level Adviser:

- SENLife Start-up
- NotJustNibbles
- NED at Cranstoun Charity

Mentoring:

- Allbright
- University of West London: Start Up School
- SheSays
- University of Planning
- FGen
- SCA
- Bloom

Thought Leadership:

- Admap
- Campaign
- Little Black Book
- Found and Flourish
- BITE
- Podcast speaker
- Public Speaker

Training

- Leadership Training
- DEI Inclusive leadership
- Advanced Presentation Skills
- APG: Data led story-telling
- D&AD Masterclass Selling Ideas
- Impact-shakers; Raising funding for impact start-ups
- APG: Mental Health First Aid
- Level 2 Certificate: Children's Mental Health

Experience

Collider I Experiential and Creative Agency

July 2017 - Sept 2019: Head of Strategy

Expanding and strengthening Collider's strategic capabilities; developing ownable IP - including a new **framework for Launch Effectiveness**, published in AdMap and a new **methodology for ROE: Return on Experience**,

Leading all branding work, including defining brand propositions, positioning and audience segmentation for Shoeaholics (part of Kurt Geiger Group); NoPla plastic free-gum, Oggs vegan bakes and Situ Live,

Working closely with the CEO and founder on New Biz, achieving a **100% pitch win rate**. Delivering campaign success and growth across a wide range of brands including: De Beers, Bookatable, Lloyds Register, SEAT, Bear Nibbles.

- Bear Nibble's Social Sampling campaign debunked the myths that healthy snacks are
 less appetising with a playful campaign, driving 42k sample requests, 4.2k new
 positive reviews on site, 87% likelihood to purchase, 4.6% Sales Growth in the UK
 and 37m impressions.
- **Bookatable** social campaign flipped the narrative from transactional to emotional tapping into FOMO x FOFU with a campaign for the diners, enabling them to dine their way, driving a **212% increase in organic daily bookings**, **96% increase in revenue** and **52% increase in site traffic.**

Developing new ways of working, cultural activities, partnerships and internal initiatives to drive change within the agency; resulting in Winning the inaugural **Women in Marketing Changemaker** award.

Jack MortonWorldwide | Global Experiential Agency; IPG Network

Nov 2016 - June 2017: VP Strategy Director Aug 2012 - Oct 2016: Senior Creative Strategist

Leading the most **challenging briefs**, on business transformation, brand launches, content strategy, employee engagement and change management, often involving multiple stakeholders. Developing **a new theory of Experiential Coding** to inform customer journey mapping. Leading the **strategy for award-winning work** for Nivea, P&G, Honda, Konica Minolta and the inaugural GREAT Festival of Creativity, and winning internal awards for impact within the agency.

- Honda at Goodwood Festival of Speed (Drum award for Best Launch & Chairman's award); developing the creative strategy, insight and proposition that led to a new creative execution for their stand; gaining press recognition; record number of visitors and exceeding lead generation targets.
- Nike: proactively developing a POV piece on how Nike market to women, informed by
 focus group insights, alongside cultural and trend analysis, crafting a proposition and
 manifesto articulating the opportunity for increasing engagement, resulting in winning
 the extremely successful launch event for a new training shoe for women.
- P&G; Future Fabrics: Developing the strategy for a media and influencer event to reposition detergent within a Fashion context; attending a 2-day R&D workshop to develop the proposition; the messaging and the experience design. Resulting advocacy and press coverage exceeded all KPIs.

Mentoring at Ad School SCA and mentoring 7 people at Jack Morton, as well as developing the Intern programme and leading the Diversity and Inclusion programme.

Education

BA (Hons) German & Psychology

Lancaster University

Award for Outstanding Performance in German

A-levels x 4St Johns Marlborough

GCSEs x 9

Pewsey Vale School
Two prizes for Academic Attainment

Languages

English: Fluent
German: Proficient
French: Basic

Experience

Central Office of Information I Govt MarComms Agency

September 2009 - March 2012: Snr Content and Brand Strategistr

Worked across all key Govt Deps, leading all areas of brand development: research, definition, naming and execution, including brand language and tone of voice. Delivering bespoke communications consultancy; applying behaviour change theory; advising on content strategies and content optimisation; running research groups and audience testing.

Managing a creative team on a range of high profile design and editorial projects across all media, developing and testing messages; producing content across multiple channels for different audience groups.. Responsible for costing, scheduling and quality control.

Redhouse Lane Communications | Independent MarComms Agency

June 2002 - Nov 2003: Head of Copy May 2001 - June 2002: Senior Copywriter

Managing a copywriting team and working closely with digital and graphic designers to communicate messages in print, online, on video or at events. Responsible for pitches and proposals, initial concepts and business planning.

Working on award-winning communication projects from brochures, websites, annual reports to direct mail and internal comms campaigns, from concepting Teaching packs for DFES Aimhigher campaign, to revising and repositioning the Boat Safety scheme handbook and leading the rebrand for the infrastructure arm of EDF.

Freelance

Sept 2000- Apr 2001: Copywriter

Writing copy for a start up; including web pages, sales messages and email marketing

Writing Sabbatical

Nov 1999- Aug 2000: Aspiring Novelist

Living in Italy for 6 months, self-taught basic Italian; writing a novel and short stories; winning a national prize for a 99word micro story.

PERSONA Management Consultants

Jan 1996 - Oct 1999: HR Consultant

Responsible for writing and marketing business case studies used for training, recruitment and development for Mars, Anheuser Busch, Virgin and PepsiCo International. **Quadrupling sales** of these training materials though dedicated marketing approach. Facilitating workshops and delivering training courses.

LEEDEX PR Company | Brunswick Group

Oct 1995 - Dec 2016: Graduate Trainee

Supporting three account managers with research, copy-editing, translation and idea generation across key FMCG accounts.

References

On request